This audio program has been produced by YBM, all rights reserved.
Listening test.
In the listening test, you will be asked to demonstrate how well you understand spoken English.
The entire listening test will last approximately 45 minutes.
There are four parts, and directions are given for each part.
You must mark your answers on the separate answer sheet.
Do not write your answers in your test book.
Part 1.
Directions For each question in this part, you will hear four statements about a picture in your test book.
When you hear the statements, you must select the one statement that best describes what you see in the picture.
Then, find the number of the question on your answer sheet and mark your answer.
The statements will not be printed in your test book and will be spoken only one time.
Look at the example item below.
Now, listen to the four statements.
A, they're moving some furniture.
B, they're entering a meeting room.
C. They're sitting at a table.
D. They're cleaning the carpet.
Statement C, they're sitting at a table, is the best description of the picture, so you should select answer C and mark it on your answer sheet.
Now, part one will begin.
Number one.
Look at the picture marked number one in your test book.
A. The man is reaching above a shelf.
B. The man is adjusting his glasses.
C. The man is paying for an item.
D. The man is trying on gloves.
Number two.
Look at the picture marked number two in your test book.
A. She's opening an umbrella over a dining area.
B. She's standing on a patio near a house.
C.
She's taking a tool out of a storage cupboard.
D. She's picking up some cushions off the ground.
Go on to the next page.
Number three.
Look at the picture marked number three in your test book.
They're raking some leaves.
B.
They're shoveling soil into a bag.
C. They're working in a garden.
D. They're watering some flowers.
Number four.
Look at the picture marked number four in your test book.
A. Some food has been laid out on platters.
B. Some chairs are lined up against the wall.
C.
Some floor tiles are being installed.
D. Some dinner plates have been placed in a sink.
Number five.
Look at the picture marked number five in your test book.
A. A worker is changing a light bulb.
A worker is handing a box to a customer.
C. A worker is crouching down behind a counter.
A worker is cleaning a window.
Number six.
Look at the picture marked number six in your test book.
A. Some potted plants are on both sides of an entrance.
B. An awning is shading a parking area.
C. Some signs are posted on a brick building.
D.
Some furniture is propping open a door.
Go on to the next page.
Part 2.
Directions.
You will hear a question or statement and three responses spoken in English.
They will not be printed in your test book and will be spoken only one time.
Select the best response to the question or statement and mark the letter A, B, or C on your answer sheet.
Now, let us begin with question number seven.
Number seven.
When will you deliver the furniture I ordered?
A. By Tuesday at the latest.
B. To several clients.
C. I bought a trailer.
Number eight.
Is your flight tomorrow or this afternoon?
A. In flight snacks.
B. It's this afternoon.
C. At baggage claim.
Number nine.
How often does the research team schedule training sessions?
A. The team leader, I think.
B.
Some new software.
C. Every other week.
Number 10.
Can I pay my bill with a credit card?
A. Sure, that's fine.
B. I don't believe him either.
C. The gas station on your right.
Number 11.
The project proposal still needs work.
A. The other office.
B. No, it's still not working.
C. I can help you with it.
Number 12.
Where do you plan to stay during your visit to the city?
A. I thought the building had 12 floors.
B.
Oh, just to present at a conference.
C. At a friend's house.
Number 13.
How did you improve the processing speed?
A. That's a question for Sylvia.
B. What's the speed limit?
C. I don't like to swim.
Number 14.
Do you take exercise classes too or just dance classes?
A. The instructor teaches in the mornings.
B. These shoes fit perfectly.
C. I only take dance.
Number 15.
When will the new coffee machine be installed in the lobby?
A.
No, it wasn't expensive.
B. The front door is unlocked.
C. Within the next few days.
Number 16.
The new marketing director will be hired soon, won't she?
A. Didn't you check your email?
B. It's about 10 minutes from here.
C.
No, a little lower.
Number 17.
I really need some help with the presentation graphics.
A. Insook can do those for you.
B. A. A conference in Chicago.
C. No.
In research and development.
Number 18.
Who can I talk to about scheduling a haircut?
A. Will you be available tomorrow afternoon?
B. Not too short on the sides, please.
C. Thanks.
The scheduling software has been helpful.
Number 19.
Did you already prepare the agenda for the department meeting?
A. We should close the windows.
B. It was postponed.
C. I bought them at the department store.
Number 20.
Do you take your coffee with or without milk?
A. The coffee shop on Bayview Avenue.
B. I prefer drinking tea.
C. We'll need to place an order for paper.
Number 21.
Why are you installing new software?
A. Because our current software is outdated.
B. We rented a large stall.
C. I'm going to wear a jacket.
Number 22.
When will next month's cost projections be ready?
A.
That portable projector was recently replaced.
B. An unexpected surplus.
C. I sent an email a few minutes ago.
Number 23.
Would you ask Tay June to help set up the product display?
A. Several kinds of headsets.
B. No, I can do it myself.
C.
I can't see the bottom line of the chart.
Number 24.
Which version of the contract do you have?
A. He's a general contractor.
B. On the second floor.
C. The final one.
Number 25.
Why isn't Ms.
Perez here yet?
A. No, I can't hear anything.
B. Company headquarters.
C. Because she's meeting with her manager.
Number 26.
I heard that our company might be merging with another one.
A. Oh, I didn't know that.
B.
A good selling product.
C. Akira told me to put it there.
Number 27.
Could you ask the next patient to come in?
A. It's in the cabinet.
B. The waiting room is empty.
C. They're both studying nursing.
Number 28.
Are the blueberries ready to harvest?
A. I'll try the strawberry flavor.
B. We have a view of the beach.
C. It's not summertime yet.
Number 29.
How long will it take us to get to the theater?
A. Tickets for the performance are sold out.
B. At 7 o'clock, I think.
C. Actually, I don't have a preference.
Number 30.
Are you going to send a report or give a presentation to our clients?
A. We enjoyed their talk.
B. I'll probably do both.
C.
20 people attended.
Number 31.
When should we hang up the posters for our conference?
A. Sure, my car will be fixed soon.
B. Next to the main entrance.
C. The design still needs to be finalized.
Part 3.
Directions.
You will hear some conversations between two or more people.
You will be asked to answer three questions about what the speakers say in each conversation.
Select the best response to each question and mark the letter A, B, C, or D on your answer sheet.
The conversations will not be printed in your test book and will be spoken only one time.
Questions 32 through 34 refer to the following conversation.
Welcome to the Firelamp Bistro.
How many for dinner?
There'll be five of us, but I'm afraid I forgot to make a reservation.
No problem.
But I should mention that we'll be closing earlier than usual this evening for a private event.
If you'd like to sit outdoors on the patio while you wait, I'll send a server to get you started with drinks and appetizers.
We'll get you seated as soon as possible.
That sounds fine, thank you.
And if possible, we'd like to sit in a quieter part of the restaurant.
We have some business to discuss.
Number 32.
What did the woman forget to do?
Number 33.
What does the man say about the restaurant?
Number 34.
What does the woman request?
Questions 35 through 37 refer to the following conversation with three speakers.
Hi, Suresh.
Office World Incorporated is thrilled about this collaboration with your company.
Your signature line of office products looks great, and we believe they'll sell quite well.
We're looking forward to partnering with you.
Thanks.
I look forward to a good working partnership as well.
And I'm proud of the fact that all my products are made with recycled materials.
I want to promote environmental responsibility.
I'm impressed.
Ah, and here is Vodika with our camera equipment.
Hello, I'm here to take some promotional photos.
I'd like to get some shots of you with your products, Suresh.
We want to post them online.
Number 35.
What is the conversation mainly about?
Number 36.
What does the man emphasize about some products?
Number 37.
Why has Vedica joined the meeting?
Questions 38 through 40 refer to the following conversation.
Highly wrong, thanks for meeting with me.
I'd like to consider advertising strategies for our bicycle shop during the annual charity bicycle race.
Well, like last year, as one of the sponsors of the event, we'll have our company name printed on the banner.
Great, but this year, I'd also like us to donate our top-of-the-line bicycle to the winner of the race to show how much we care about our community.
That's a nice idea.
But sponsoring the race is already going to be costly.
I'm worried about the added expense of donating a bicycle as well.
Number 38.
What event are the speakers discussing?
Number 39.
What does the man suggest doing this year?
Number 40.
What concern does the woman express?
Questions 41 through 43 refer to the following conversation.
Welcome, Farida, and here's your identification badge.
My name's Malik Al-Jahani.
I'm a senior engineer, and during your first 60 days at Tilmer Tech,
I'll be mentoring you throughout the new employee onboarding process.
I'm glad to be here.
Your company's one of the top manufacturers of robotic vacuum cleaners in the country.
Since I just graduated from university, it's exciting to be applying all that theory directly to this engineering job.
Absolutely.
And right now, we're headed to your first activity for today.
Like all new engineers here, you'll be tasked with taking apart and reassembling our top-selling product.
It's a first step in helping you become knowledgeable about how our product functions.
Number 41.
Who is the man?
Number 42.
What product does the company manufacture?
Number 43.
What will the woman most likely do next?
Go on to the next page.
Questions 44 through 46 refer to the following conversation.
Hey, Joty, I can't believe it.
You know how I told you that I won some tickets to my favorite basketball team's championship for this weekend?
Well, now I can't go.
Why?
What happened?
You look really disappointed.
One of my clients has requested a rush on their order.
I'll need to do a quality check on all the products so we can ship by Monday morning.
Well, I'm free this weekend.
Why don't I take over for you?
Just let your supervisor know that I can do the quality check.
You can help me out next weekend.
Number 44.
What was the man hoping to do this weekend?
Number 45.
Why does the man need to cancel his plans?
Number 46.
What does the woman offer to do?
Questions 47 through 49 refer to the following conversation.
I understand that you found a good candidate to deliver the keynote speech at our conference.
I have.
Dr. Murad Jabrine.
He's a specialist in sports medicine.
and he's developed new surgical techniques for athletes with knee injuries.
His new book on the topic will be published later this month, actually.
Oh, yes, I've heard of him.
I wonder if we have enough money to give copies to everyone who comes to the conference.
I can check our budget.
Number 47.
What was the man asked to do in preparation for a conference?
Number 48.
Who is the conference intended for?
Number 49.
What does the woman want to hand out to conference attendees?
Questions 50 through 52 refer to the following conversation.
Hi, I'm calling about your advertisement.
I currently rent a space downtown where I build and repair furniture, but the owners just sold the building and I have to be out by the end of the month.
Well, my space is quite large, enough to fit two cars or a work truck.
It also has a dock in the back to load large containers, if that would be useful to you.
Ideally, yes.
I build large items and a loading dock would make pickup and delivery easier.
Would you like to see it this afternoon?
Currently there's no electricity, but I could call and have it turned on today.
Number 50.
Who is the woman?
Number 51.
What does the man highlight about a workspace?
Number 52.
What does the man offer to do for the woman?
Questions 53 through 55 refer to the following conversation.
Masim, I know this is last minute, but is there any chance we can add another section to the workbook for tomorrow's seminar?
Oh, the workbook's already been printed.
I see.
I just learned that the company added a new policy about working with clients that we need to include.
Well, why don't we just add an insert to each copy of the workbook before we pass them out?
Then everyone will be informed of the change.
Number 53.
What are the speakers preparing for?
Number 54.
What does the man imply when he says, The workbook's already been printed.
Number 55.
What does the man suggest?
Questions 56 through 58 refer to the following conversation.
Hi, Astrid.
Thank you for meeting with me.
Of course.
I have an open-door policy for all my employees here at the factory.
So I'd like to talk about changing my work schedule to the day shift.
Well, we've had a lot of requests for that lately.
I see.
But remember, I've been working the night shift for over 10 years.
That's true.
Let me look into it.
I'll check the schedule and see what I can do.
No promises, though.
Number 56.
Who most likely is the woman?
Number 57.
Why does the woman say... We've had a lot of requests for that lately.
Number 58.
What does the woman say she will do?
Questions 59 through 61 refer to the following conversation with three speakers.
I have bad news.
Ifay just sent me a text message.
Her car won't start.
The battery seems to be dead.
She won't be here in time to lead her tour group.
Oh no.
Well, I'm leading a tour of the seaport this morning.
Rajiv, you're available.
I know you're technically still in training, but I think you can handle it.
Hmm.
The historic warehouse district, right?
I'm a little nervous about that.
You did a great job when you shadowed me on that tour last week.
You even answered questions from the group.
Number 59.
What news does the woman share?
Number 60.
Who are the men?
Number 61.
Why is Rajiv nervous?
Question 62 through 64 refer to the following conversation and road lane diagram.
We need to check with the project manager about today's construction schedule.
I already did.
I just came from his office.
He said we're going to close off multiple lanes to create a safe work zone.
Got it.
Which ones are we closing?
All of them, except for the passing lane.
Wow.
This closure is really going to affect the morning commute.
You're right.
I'm going to ask for extra personnel to help manage the traffic volume.
Number 62.
Where has the woman just come from?
Number 63.
Look at the graphic.
Which lane will stay open today?
Number 64.
What does the woman say she will ask for?
Go on to the next page.
Question 65 through 67 refer to the following conversation and schedule.
Let's start planning the annual employee retreat.
Yes.
I think we should hold it outside.
We're at our desks all day, so it would be really great to spend some time in the sun.
I agree.
There's a place Oliver's Orchard that lets you pick your own fruit.
We could have the event there.
Great idea.
The retreat's in June.
Is it open then?
According to the website they are.
Perfect.
I'll call the Orchard to make a reservation for our group.
Number 65.
What does the woman suggest about an event location?
Number 66.
Look at the graphic.
Which fruit will be picked during the event?
Number 67.
What does the woman say she will do?
Question 68 through 70 refer to the following conversation and map.
Hi, I'm looking for an apartment, and I saw your advertisement.
Do you have any two-bedroom apartments available in May?
Yes.
In fact, we've just finished construction on a new complex.
Does the complex have a lot of outdoor space?
I'd like to have an area to entertain guests outside.
Yes, there's plenty of green space.
The building in the back corner, farthest from the office, has the most space and a lot of shade.
I'd be interested in that.
And for an extra $80 per month, you can get a reserved parking space right in front of your unit.
Number 68.
Who most likely is the woman?
Number 69.
Look at the graphic.
Which location is the woman referring to?
Number 70.
What might the man pay extra for?
Part 4.
Directions You will hear some talks given by a single speaker.
You will be asked to answer three questions about what the speaker says in each talk.
Select the best response to each question and mark the letter A, B, C, or D on your answer sheet.
The talks will not be printed in your test book and will be spoken only one time.
Question 71 through 73 refer to the following excerpt from a meeting.
Some of you have been accidentally skipping some of your closing duties, so I've called this meeting to clarify what is expected.
After you've sanitized all the food preparation areas in the kitchen, make sure the pantry and walk-in refrigerator doors are shut and locked.
There are a few other tasks to complete before you leave.
I know the current checklist isn't up to date, so I'll make the necessary revisions to it.
Number 71 What is the purpose of a meeting?
Number 72.
What type of business do the listeners most likely work for?
Number 73.
What does the speaker say he will do?
Question 74 through 76 refer to the following telephone message.
Hi Melissa, it's Hi Hiroki from Ecology Now magazine.
I just read your article about protecting old growth forests in Europe and how important these conservation efforts are to the local communities.
First of all, I loved your descriptions of the mushroom hunting social groups.
Readers will feel like they're there.
However,
Your article mainly presents the views of people who use the forests for recreation.
We need to hear from the lawmakers responsible for the new regulations impacting land use.
And be sure to include some photos.
Aside from that, great job.
Call me back if you want more guidance.
Number 74.
What topic did the listener write an article about?
Number 75.
What does the speaker like about the article?
Number 76.
Who does the speaker want the listener to interview?
Question 77 through 79, refer to the following talk.
Welcome, everyone, to this workshop on artificial intelligence technologies.
Though I know everyone's been enjoying the coffee in conversation, we have a lot of speakers on the schedule.
To start things off, we're delighted to invite Dr. Haruka Adachi to the stage.
She'll demonstrate some ways computer systems can simulate human intelligence.
Even if you're not a computer programmer, I'm sure you'll find this demonstration easy to follow.
Please feel free to raise your hand to ask questions at any time.
We want these sessions to be interactive.
Number 77.
What does the speaker imply when she says... We have a lot of speakers on the schedule.
Number 78.
What industry does Dr. Adachi most likely work in?
Number 79.
What does the speaker encourage the listeners to do?
Questions 80 through 82 refer to the following announcement.
Attention everyone.
The Home Bathroom Showcase will begin in an hour in Hall D. The showcase will feature the latest designs for showers and bathtubs, as well as a variety of materials for home customization.
Exhibitors, please be at your designated booth at least 30 minutes before the showcase opens to the public.
If you need assistance, any staff member can direct you to your booth.
Attendees, don't forget to bring your tickets to the showcase.
We will be running a raffle with a chance to win a new bathtub.
You'll need your ticket to participate.
Number 80.
What type of event is most likely taking place?
Number 81.
What are exhibitors asked to do?
Number 82.
What does the speaker say attendees can do with their tickets?
Go on to the next page.
Questions 83 through 85 refer to the following telephone message.
Hi, Andrew.
I'm calling about the Dearborn Hotel account.
the clients that we're producing the television commercial for.
I just heard from them, and they said they've been very satisfied with how you're addressing their needs for the project.
It's always great to get such positive feedback from our clients, and this is your first account.
They also mentioned that they'd like to make some adjustments to the project timeline.
Could you email me the most recent copy of it?
Thanks.
Number 83
What industry does the speaker most likely work in?
Number 84.
What does the speaker mean when she says, This is your first account?
Number 85.
What does the speaker ask the listener to send?
Questions 86 through 88 refer to the following talk.
Hi, everyone.
As farm employees, we have all come across various issues with our equipment.
Today, I'm going to talk about what to do when you find liquid leaking from any of our farm equipment.
Our mowers and tractors mainly use fluids like water or oil to control steering.
When you find fluid leaking from a broken tube or valve, don't try to fix it yourself.
Please let me know, and I'll contact the manufacturer for a replacement part.
Otherwise, the warranty will be voided.
Number 86.
Where do the listeners most likely work?
Number 87.
What is the speaker mainly discussing?
Number 88.
What solution does the speaker suggest?
Questions 89 through 91 refer to the following announcement.
Good afternoon and thanks for visiting Eastgate Art Museum.
This month, we're delighted to offer a special exhibit of Johann Weber's paintings.
In just a few minutes, our museum director will be giving a talk in the museum theatre about the artist's life and work.
While you're here, please consider becoming a member of the museum.
To sign up, stop by the information desk.
Members will receive advance notice about educational events, like the one today.
Number 89.
Who is Johann Weber?
Number 90.
What will take place momentarily?
Number 91.
According to the speaker,
What can the listeners do at the information desk?
Questions 92 through 94 refer to the following excerpt from a meeting.
This chart shows the clinic's average monthly expenses.
Our wages for dental hygienists, assistants, and other staff members are about 25% of the budget, which is right on target.
Even though our rent has gradually increased over the years, it still doesn't take up a large part of our budget.
However, look at the costs of our supplies.
You know, we haven't looked at other suppliers recently.
Any savings we might find could be used for marketing to help bring in more business.
So where could we focus our marketing efforts?
Number 92.
Where does the speaker most likely work?
Number 93.
What does the speaker imply when she says... We haven't looked at other suppliers recently.
Number 94.
What will most likely be discussed next?
Questions 95 through 97 refer to the following telephone message and chart.
Hi, I'm calling to purchase some backpacks for my company.
We recently started selling textbooks, and our employees will be traveling regionally to sell them.
I'd like to provide the backpacks to our customers as promotional gifts, but I'd like them to be sturdy, so I'd like something with padded straps to make them comfortable.
And there should be easy access to a water bottle as well.
If you have what we need, we plan to order 50 of these.
So can you tell me if there is a bulk discount?
Please call me back at 5550198.
Number 95.
Why does the speaker want to purchase backpacks?
Number 96.
Look at the graphic.
Which backpack fits the speaker's needs?
Number 97.
What does the speaker ask about?
Questions 98 through 100 refer to the following excerpt from a meeting and sign.
Hi, everyone.
As most of you know, I opened this grocery store five years ago.
I'm happy that we are the main supplier of fruits and vegetables in the neighborhood, and the demand for our products has increased.
To meet this need, we've received a loan that will allow us to expand our operations.
These additional funds will allow us to make an important change.
Effective immediately, we'll be open seven days a week.
That means we'll have extra shifts available.
If you'd like to work one of these extra shifts, please let me know.
Number 98.
What type of business does the speaker run?
Number 99.
According to the speaker,
What did the business receive?
Number 100.
Look at the graphic.
Which day will the business hours change?