This audio program has been produced by YBM, all rights reserved.
Listening test.
In the listening test, you will be asked to demonstrate how well you understand spoken English.
The entire listening test will last approximately 45 minutes.
There are four parts, and directions are given for each part.
You must mark your answers on the separate answer sheet.
Do not write your answers in your test book.
Part 1.
Directions For each question in this part, you will hear four statements about a picture in your test book.
When you hear the statements, you must select the one statement that best describes what you see in the picture.
Then, find the number of the question on your answer sheet and mark your answer.
the statements will not be printed in your test book and will be spoken only one time.
Look at the example item below.
Now, listen to the four statements.
A, they're moving some furniture.
B, they're entering a meeting room.
C. They're sitting at a table.
D. They're cleaning the carpet.
Statements C, they're sitting at a table, is the best description of the picture, so you should select answer C and mark it on your answer sheet.
Now, part one will begin.
Number one.
Look at the picture marked number one in your test book.
A. She's shoveling snow from a walkway.
B. She's using walking sticks.
C.
She's removing her cap.
D. She's drinking from a water bottle.
Number two.
Look at the picture marked number two in your test book.
A. A woman is carrying a tray.
B. A woman is pushing a food trolley.
C. Some people are leaving a restaurant.
D.
Some diners are looking out a window.
Go on to the next page.
Number three, look at the picture marked number three in your test book.
A. The man is holding a bucket of water.
B. The man is replacing a tire.
C. The man is watering a tree.
The man is scrubbing the front of a car.
Number four.
Look at the picture marked number four in your test book.
A. Some tiles are being installed on a roof.
B. An outdoor dining area is unoccupied.
C. Flowers have been placed on tables.
D.
Some chairs have been arranged around a fountain.
Number five.
Look at the picture marked number five in your test book.
A. Some people are gathered on top of a building.
B. Some trees are blocking the entrance to a stairway.
C. A woman is taking some stairs to a lower level.
D.
A woman is walking across a pedestrian bridge.
Number six.
Look at the picture marked number six in your test book.
A. Some wooden planter boxes have been set next to each other.
B. Some wood logs have been piled in a corner.
C. The outside walls of a house are made of bricks.
D.
Some windows are being installed.
Go on to the next page.
Part 2.
Directions.
You will hear a question or statement and three responses spoken in English.
They will not be printed in your test book and will be spoken only one time.
Select the best response to the question or statement and mark the letter A, B, or C on your answer sheet.
Now, let us begin with question number seven.
Number seven.
Who's going to take home the leftover cake?
A. Marcel said he would.
B. A lovely selection of desserts.
C. No, I thought it started at noon.
Number eight.
Can you tell me where the security office is?
A. Today's my first day here.
B. A photograph for the badge.
C. Because it's after lunch.
Number nine.
What's the best way to contact you?
A. On my mobile phone.
B.
No, I have to wear glasses.
C. This resume is better.
Number 10.
Who's joining us for the waterfront boat ride?
A. Conference Room 3.
B. The admission fee is reasonable.
C. Everybody on our team is coming.
Number 11.
Could you request a technician to repair the packaging machine?
A. Three years of technical school.
B. Sure, I'll do that.
C. The blue one with gold trim.
Number 12.
How many copies of the proposal should I make?
A. There's blue paper in the cabinet.
B. Yes, it was my idea.
C.
50 should be enough for everyone.
Number 13.
Why is Jonathan leaving early?
A. To catch the 6 o'clock train.
B. On the early morning news.
C. That's where he lives now.
Number 14.
Where's the company party being held?
A. It's a publishing firm.
B. Party of five at the table in the corner.
C. At the Chesterville Hotel.
Number 15.
Did you want to sign up for a one-year magazine subscription?
A. How much will it cost?
B.
Near the service center.
C. Archico works at the front desk.
Number 16.
Does this pasta come with a side salad?
A. We do have a tablecloth.
B. No, I'm afraid not.
C. I like it too.
Number 17.
When can we meet about the invoices?
A. Supplies for the office.
B. I'm free after two.
C. Probably on Harold's desk.
Number 18.
Would you like me to help you open a savings account?
A. I've already counted them.
B.
That'd be great.
C.
50 euros each.
Number 19.
When did you post the job opening?
A. On the bulletin board in the hallway.
B. It's been on the website for a month.
C. Can you close the door?
Number 20.
Are you applying for the manager position?
A. About 16 more employees.
B. I'll check her schedule again.
C. Yes, I hope I get it.
Number 21.
Are you traveling in business class or economy?
A. My flight was just canceled.
B.
My focus is history.
C. London, then New York.
Number 22.
The number of subscribers for our magazine has decreased recently.
A. There's room in the budget for more advertising.
B. An annual membership fee.
C. There are six folders on the table.
Number 23.
How do you clean the solar panels without damaging them?
A. The glass can be any color you want.
B. No, the sun isn't out today.
C. I pay a company to do all the maintenance.
Number 24.
When will I receive my certificate in the mail?
A.
I'll have to check with the office.
B. Turn left at the light.
C. No, thank you.
Number 25.
Don't we sell Ramirez lawnmowers?
A. The plants need more water.
B. Sorry, refunds are not allowed.
C. I work in the home decor area.
Number 26.
Should we meet to discuss our research project?
A. A publishing manual.
B. Put something on my calendar.
C. Alphabetical order is fine, I think.
Number 27.
When does the cleaning staff leave for the day?
A. A supply closet in the hall.
B.
By 6 o'clock, usually.
C. The leaves come out in the spring.
Number 28.
How would you like to pay for these shoes today?
A. With a store gift card.
B. I wear a size 38.
C. A friend recommended them.
Number 29.
It's an effective advertisement, isn't it?
A. I've heard that sales have increased.
B. The next issue of the magazine.
C. Isn't the policy in effect already?
Number 30.
Why don't we take a walk after lunch?
A. The sales report is due at 1 o'clock.
No, in parking area B. C. I'll have spaghetti, please.
Number 31.
I decided to move the seasonal merchandise to the front of the store.
A. Did you put some of it in the window display?
B. For our summer clothing collection.
C. The moving van is coming tomorrow.
Part 3.
Directions.
You will hear some conversations between two or more people.
You will be asked to answer three questions about what the speakers say in each conversation.
Select the best response to each question and mark the letter A, B, C, or D on your answer sheet.
The conversations will not be printed in your test book and will be spoken only one time.
Questions 32 through 34 refer to the following conversation.
The renovations we're planning for the theatre are long overdue.
I'm glad we have time between productions so we can get the work done.
I agree.
And even though it's great that our latest musical production has had such a successful run, we can all use the break.
Plus, it gives us time to focus on next month's fundraiser.
Hopefully we'll raise enough money at that event to replace the old lighting system too.
Number 32.
What are the speakers mainly discussing?
Number 33.
What does the man say about a musical production?
Number 34.
What event are the speakers planning?
Questions 35 through 37 refer to the following conversation.
Fernanda, I wanted to tell you that the top candidate we chose for the customer care position just accepted our job offer.
I'll send him a contract later today.
Great.
But now I think we need a bigger office space for our business.
With the new hire, there will be 10 of us in the office.
I agree.
Our lease expires next month, so we should look at a different space.
There's a new office building on 2nd Street.
It has solar panels, so all of its energy comes from renewable sources.
I like that, but I'm worried we may not be able to afford the lease.
We'll see.
I'll contact the rental agency today.
Number 35.
What did the speakers recently do?
Number 36.
What do the speakers like about a building?
Number 37.
What is the woman worried about?
Questions 38 through 40 refer to the following conversation.
How can I help you?
Hi, I'd like to order a cake for my son's birthday next week.
He really likes dinosaurs.
I have several different dinosaur-shaped pans for you to choose from.
Actually, I was hoping you could make a standing cake instead of a flat one.
Oh, I see.
I'm sorry.
I do have someone on staff who can make those.
But she's all booked up for the next few weeks.
Try Carmen's creations on Pine Street.
Number 38.
What event is the woman planning?
Number 39.
Who most likely is the man?
Number 40.
Why does the man apologize?
Questions 41 through 43 refer to the following conversation.
Hello, you've reached quick phone repair service.
Hi, I went online to schedule a repair for my mobile phone, but all appointments in your store were booked for today.
Have you had any cancellations?
No, unfortunately not.
What's the problem with your phone?
The phone only lasts about an hour before it has to be recharged.
It sounds like you need a new battery.
If you come to the store now, we can try to fit you in as a walk-in appointment.
You may have to wait around for a bit.
I don't mind waiting.
Number 41.
What did the man try to do online?
Number 42.
What does the man say is wrong with his mobile phone?
Number 43.
What will the man most likely do next?
Go on to the next page.
Questions 44 through 46 refer to the following conversation.
Asako, how far along are you on that news report about the bank merger?
If you wanted to be included in tomorrow morning's newspaper, it has to be on my desk by 9 p.m.
Well, I'm still doing research for this article.
I'm having trouble getting all the facts from the people involved.
They haven't returned my phone calls.
Well, we can't print the story without confirming the details.
But if you can have it finished by Wednesday night, I can put it in Thursday's paper.
Number 44.
Where do the speakers most likely work?
Number 45.
Why has the woman been unable to finish a task?
Number 46.
What solution does the man propose?
Questions 47 through 49 refer to the following conversation.
We'll have to remove the soil from the garden bed and lay down drain pipes that'll take the water out through holes in the retaining wall.
Sounds like a lot of work.
But it'll be worth it to be able to grow the garden that I want to.
Do you think you'd like bricks or stones for the retaining wall?
Many homeowners prefer brick because it creates a nice, uniform look, but stones will last longer.
They are more expensive, though.
I don't want to have to make repairs.
You have several different kinds of stones to choose from.
I have some pictures of projects I've completed in the past you can look at.
Number 47
What kind of work does the man do?
Number 48.
What does the woman imply when she says, I don't want to have to make repairs?
Number 49.
What will the man show to the woman show to the woman?
Questions 50 through 52 refer to the following conversation.
Good morning.
You've reached accounts payable.
Hi, I'm calling from the editorial department.
One of our freelance writers has not received payment yet, so I'm calling to inquire about it.
Her contract number is 9356.
Okay, let me check.
Hmm.
It looks like she should have been paid last week.
But Adem handles those requests and he was on vacation.
He's just catching up today.
Do you have an estimate of how long it will take to process the request?
I'm not sure, but I can speak to Adem.
Number 50.
Why is the man calling?
Number 51.
According to the woman...
What caused a delay?
Number 52.
What information will the woman most likely provide later?
Questions 53 through 55 refer to the following conversation with three speakers.
I'm the general manager here at Revit Auto Repair, and this is Mr. Singh, our service manager.
We're eager to hear how your product can benefit our shop.
Well, my product is called Video Room.
It's a library of short videos that your business can offer in the waiting room.
These videos will explain common auto repairs and educate your customers on the repair process.
Can we add our own customized content?
I'd love to include a description of our exclusive lifetime warranty.
Yes.
And can we also add at-home auto care advice?
Number 53.
Where does the conversation take place?
Number 54.
What type of product does the woman mention?
Number 55.
What do the men want to do?
Questions 56 through 58 refer to the following conversation.
Hi, Carmen.
I've just reviewed the outline you gave me for the nature documentary we're making.
I think it'll be a great film, but I'm a bit concerned.
I want it to be less than an hour.
I understand.
I'll take another look at it and see where I can take out some unnecessary scenes from the storyboard.
Great.
In the meantime, I need to follow up with our camera team to make sure they have all the equipment they need to begin filming.
Number 56.
What industry do the speakers most likely work in?
Number 57.
What does the man imply when he says, I want it to be less than an hour?
Number 58.
Why does the man need to contact a team?
Questions 59 through 61 refer to the following conversation with three speakers.
Creti and Melissa I reviewed the results of the soil tests yesterday and most of the sports fields we manage have healthy soil.
But unfortunately, the baseball field on Smith Drive has elevated levels of potassium.
The grass on that field is so brown and weedy.
Now we know why.
We'll need to order some special fertilizer to put on it.
Do you think we need approval to do that?
Yes, since it's an unforeseen expense, it has to be approved by the acquisitions department.
Melissa, do you have time to prepare a cost estimate?
Sure, it won't take long.
I'll send it by lunchtime, and I'll CC you both on the email.
Number 59.
What did the man review yesterday?
Number 60.
What do the speakers hope to do?
Number 61.
What will Melissa send by email?
Question 62 through 64 refer to the following conversation and schedule.
Rodrigo, you wanted to talk to me about the schedule for the bowling leagues at our alley?
Yes.
As you know, many of the members in the adult league have young children who participate in the junior league.
And they explained to me that it would be really convenient if we moved the junior league to the same night that the adult league plays.
That way they could all come together on the same night.
That's a great idea.
We have a few available bowling lanes on that day that the junior league can use.
I'll email the parents of the junior bowlers and let them know the day will change starting next month.
Number 62.
Where do the speakers work?
Number 63.
Look at the graphic.
On which day will the junior league meet starting next month?
Number 64.
What does the woman say she will do?
Go on to the next page.
Question 65 through 67 refer to the following conversation and calendar.
Hi, where can I find a schedule of library events?
Oh, I've got it right here.
We usually have events almost every day, but we're closed this Friday.
The library is being used for the district elections.
I see.
Are there any movies showing?
Yes.
There's one on Thursday evening.
Oh, too bad.
I'm away for a client meeting on Thursday.
Well, if you like Sumit Mehta's books, you might be interested in his book signing.
I do like his novels.
Thanks.
I'll come back for that.
Number 65.
According to the woman, why will the library be closed on Friday?
Number 66.
What schedule conflict does the man mention?
Number 67.
Look at the graphic.
When will the man most likely attend a library event?
Question 68 through 70 refer to the following conversation and paint options.
Good news, Tariq.
We'll have enough money to make those repairs to the bridge over the fish pond that you mentioned.
We've been awarded a grant to make some repairs to the park grounds.
That's great.
That bridge needs a new coat of paint to protect it from the elements.
I think I sent you a list of paint colours when I first talked to you about the project.
You did.
Because it's such an iconic symbol of the park, and it's in so many photographs, we want it to be as close to the original colour as when it was first built, even though that's the most expensive option on the list.
Number 68.
What is the conversation about?
Number 69.
According to the woman, how is a project being funded?
Number 70.
Look at the graphic.
Which color does the woman select?
Part 4.
Directions You will hear some talks given by a single speaker.
You will be asked to answer three questions about what the speaker says in each talk.
Select the best response to each question and mark the letter A, B, C or D on your answer sheet.
The talks will not be printed in your test book and will be spoken only one time.
Question 71 through 73 refer to the following talk.
Hi everyone, big news.
Our clinic is getting a check-in kiosk.
What this means is that patients will be able to check themselves into their medical appointments by clicking through some buttons in the kiosk.
You will no longer have to do it for them.
I know all of you have been very busy answering phones, scheduling appointments and checking patients in.
So hopefully this helps to make your work easier.
We'll have a very short training session next Tuesday on how the check-in kiosk works.
Number 71
Where does the talk most likely take place?
Number 72.
What is mainly being discussed?
Number 73.
What will happen next Tuesday?
Question 74 through 76, refer to the following podcast.
Welcome to a new episode of tomorrow's technology.
Today, we'll be talking about drones.
If you're planning to buy your first drone, here are a few things you need to know.
To begin with, if you want to use the device for commercial purposes, such as photography or videography, then you'll need to apply for a license.
I'll share some resources at the end of this podcast to guide your application process.
Number 74.
Who is the podcast intended for?
Number 75.
According to the speaker, what will some listeners need?
Number 76.
What information will the speaker share?
Question 77 through 79 refer to the following announcement.
Attention Exhibitors.
Welcome to the Digital Signage Expo, where representatives selling digital billboards and video displays can interact directly with buyers.
The exhibit hall will open in 15 minutes.
To ensure everyone's safety, we request that you clear your exhibit area of boxes and debris, and be sure cables and electrical cords are securely taped to the floor.
And remember, the exhibit hall will close at 5 p.m.
today so that exhibitors can attend this evening's reception.
That will be held in the building's main lobby.
Number 77.
Who are the listeners?
Number 78.
What does the speaker request that the listeners do?
Number 79.
What will take place in the evening?
Questions 80 through 82 refer to the following advertisement.
Welcome to Money Reveals, the podcast for smart investors.
This week, I'll be discussing the best tips for amateur investors if you're just getting started.
But first, this episode is brought to you by Code Word.
Don't search online for discount coupons any longer.
Code Word is a software application that scans the Internet for promotional codes and applies them to your online shopping cart.
If Code Word finds any discounts, an apply coupon button will automatically appear at checkout.
What's more, the first 100 listeners to use the download link on my website will receive free music festival tickets.
Number 80.
Who most likely is the speaker?
Number 81.
According to the speaker, what can a software application be used for?
Number 82.
How can the listeners receive some free tickets?
Go on to the next page.
Questions 83 through 85 refer to the following telephone message.
Hi, this is Sujin, in Apartment 2A.
I just moved into the complex last month.
I'm calling about a problem with my kitchen sink.
The drain is completely clogged so the water won't go down.
I've tried a few different drain cleaning products, but they didn't help.
I think I've done all I can do.
I'm at work now, but I'll be home this afternoon.
Could you call me back so we can arrange a time to meet there?
Thanks.
Number 83.
Who is the speaker most likely calling?
Number 84.
What problem does the speaker have?
Number 85.
Why does the speaker say, I think I've done all I can do.
Questions 86 through 88 refer to the following excerpt from a meeting.
Next Tuesday, the 11th is our office cleanup.
We'll have bins stationed all around the office for you to put garbage and recycling in.
Be sure to shred any documents that have private client information on them.
Our office manager, Rajiv, has rented some extra document shredders for us to use.
Thanks for taking care of that, Rajeev.
Now, we've hired two new accountants who are supposed to start in a month, and we need to make space for their desks.
Now that our work is mostly paperless, the south corner of the office has a lot of empty file cabinets.
Number 86.
What will the listeners do next Tuesday?
Number 87
What does the speaker thank Rajeev for doing?
Number 88.
Why does the speaker say, The south corner of the office has a lot of empty file cabinets.
Questions 89 through 91 refer to the following recorded message.
Hello, and thank you for calling Ziegler Incorporated, the area's top supplier of office paper.
Due to bad weather conditions last week, roads around our warehouse were closed.
As a result, customers may be experiencing delays in receiving their recent orders.
Now that the roads are clear, we've resumed deliveries.
However, we'll need a few days to catch up.
To make up for this inconvenience, we're offering customers a 20% discount on their next purchase.
To claim the discount, enter your invoice number on our website.
Once you do, your discount code will arrive in an email.
Number 89.
What does Ziegler Incorporated sell?
Number 90.
According to the speaker, what problem is the company experiencing?
Number 91.
What will arrive in an email?
Questions 92 through 94 refer to the following excerpt from a meeting.
As members of the City's Arts Commission, it's our responsibility to manage arts programs and initiatives.
The Mayor's decision to redevelop the Hoverton District is welcome news across the community.
And for our Commission, it's an opportunity to integrate sculptures into public spaces there.
We'll need to determine what overall community themes should be addressed and prioritized.
So I think it's important that we conduct a survey regarding the residents' preferences.
It's a diverse community with a range of perspectives to consider.
And, of course, in order for the artwork to be built, we'll need to hire a skilled artist for the task.
I think Alvaro Gomez has won several awards.
Number 92
What has the mayor decided to do?
Number 93.
What is the goal of a survey?
Number 94.
Why does the speaker say, I think Alvaro Gomez has won several awards.
Questions 95 through 97 refer to the following message and seating chart.
Good afternoon, Mr. Kwan.
This is Olga Popova from the Smith Theatre.
You're next on the wait list for theatre tickets.
On your preference form, you requested four tickets together in either the orchestra or the mid balcony.
Unfortunately, those sections are completely sold out on the date you requested.
But I do have four tickets together in the lower balcony for that date.
I'll be happy to set aside those tickets if you'd like.
I can hold this request for 24 hours.
Please call our box office as soon as possible to let me know if you're still interested.
Number 95.
Who most likely is the speaker?
Number 96.
Look at the graphics.
How much do tickets in the available section cost?
Number 97.
What does the listener need to do within 24 hours?
Questions 98 through 100 refer to the following tour information and map.
Welcome to this bus tour of the Kenzie Harbor.
Unfortunately, one of the stops on our itinerary, the museum, is closed, and we won't be able to visit it.
The museum had a water pipe burst overnight.
It looks like repair and cleanup work will last this whole week.
I apologize.
since I know many of you were looking forward to seeing the museum's exhibit on local fish.
To make up for this, we're providing complimentary meal vouchers so you can enjoy a free lunch on us when we get to the area around the cannery.
Number 98.
Look at the graphic.
Which stop has been cancelled?
Number 99.
Why has a stop been canceled?
Number 100.
What will the listeners receive?