This audio program has been produced by YBM, all rights reserved.
Listening test.
In the listening test, you will be asked to demonstrate how well you understand spoken English.
The entire listening test will last approximately 45 minutes.
There are four parts, and directions are given for each part.
You must mark your answers on the separate answer sheet.
Do not write your answers in your test book.
Part 1.
Directions For each question in this part, you will hear four statements about a picture in your test book.
When you hear the statements, you must select the one statement that best describes what you see in the picture.
Then, find the number of the question on your answer sheet and mark your answer.
the statements will not be printed in your test book and will be spoken only one time.
Look at the example item below.
Now, listen to the four statements.
A, they're moving some furniture.
B, they're entering a meeting room.
C. They're sitting at a table.
D. They're cleaning the carpet.
Statements C, they're sitting at a table, is the best description of the picture, so you should select answer C and mark it on your answer sheet.
Now, part one will begin.
Number one.
Look at the picture marked number one in your test book.
A. The worker is carrying some plants.
B. The worker is reading a sign.
C.
The worker is pushing a cart.
D. The worker is writing some notes.
Number two.
Look at the picture marked number two in your test book.
A. Some of the people are pulling suitcases.
B. Some of the people are relaxing on benches.
C. Some of the people are putting luggage onto Iraq.
Some of the people are waiting in line to purchase a ticket.
Go on to the next page.
Number three.
Look at the picture marked number three in your test book.
A. She's looking into her backpack.
B. She's tying the laces of her boots.
C. She's hiking on an outdoor path.
D. She's walking out of a tunnel.
Number four.
Look at the picture marked number four in your test book.
A. He's holding the handle of a shopping cart.
B. He's plugging a cord into a wall outlet.
C. He's looking into a kitchen cupboard.
D.
He's kneeling down on a tile floor.
Number five.
Look at the picture marked number five in your test book.
A. Seats have been arranged under some umbrellas.
B. Some street signs are being taken down.
C. Some bushes are being trimmed.
D.
Some chairs are being folded and stacked.
Number six.
Look at the picture marked number six in your test book.
A. Some cushions have been laid on the floor.
B. Books have been piled up by a glass door.
C. A light fixture is suspended from the ceiling.
D.
A rug has been rolled up against a wall.
Go on to the next page.
Part 2.
Directions.
You will hear a question or statement and three responses spoken in English.
They will not be printed in your test book and will be spoken only one time.
Select the best response to the question or statement and mark the letter A, B, or C on your answer sheet.
Now, let us begin with question number seven.
Number seven.
There's a meeting in the conference room soon, right?
A. Yes, it's for the whole department.
B. No, put it in the closet.
C. The rent is too high.
Number eight.
Why hasn't the mural in the lobby been painted yet?
A. Red and yellow.
B. Please pick up the ladder.
C. Because the artist is out of town.
Number nine.
Do you prefer writing in the morning or the afternoon?
A. My publisher requested edits.
B. Thanks for providing a solution.
C. Mornings are usually better for me.
Number 10.
I suggest we paint the waiting room light blue.
A. Dr. Park has an opening at 3.
B. That's a good idea.
C. I prefer the red jacket.
Number 11.
Did you know that the music school is closed on Sundays?
A.
$40 an hour.
B. No, I didn't know that.
C. I saw the piano recital.
Number 12.
How do I find the office manager?
A. The receptionist would know.
B. Desk lamps and headsets.
C.
12 euros.
Number 13.
When did you place the order for the lumber?
A. Yes, it's a great place for hiking.
B. It's out of stock right now.
C. The warehouse on William Street.
Number 14.
Where is the new packaging machine?
A.
10 packages a minute.
B. We met last Thursday.
C. We decided to keep the old one.
Number 15.
I'll be out of the office this afternoon.
A. An awfully long commute.
B. Okay.
I'll update your schedule.
C. It's right down the hallway.
Number 16.
Are you taking a vacation once this project is over?
A. Yes, I'm planning a trip to Barcelona.
B. This is your second time, isn't it?
C. Blueprints for a high-rise building.
Number 17.
Let's post the sales report to our team's webpage.
A. We're sharing a taxi to the airport.
B. I can do that.
C. A recent hiring decision.
Number 18.
Which airline are you planning on using?
A. The usual one.
B.
A one-way ticket.
C. Yes, you can use mine.
Number 19.
Where's this shipment of parts being sent?
A. Around 5.30 this evening.
B. To the assembly plant in Dublin.
C. Just half the order.
Number 20.
Who paid for lunch?
A. I just ate.
B. It closes at five.
C. Alberto did.
Number 21.
How many employees work in your department?
A. I don't mind taking notes at the meeting.
B. A. A. A. A. A. A. A. A couple dozen, I think.
C. It's seven meters long.
Number 22.
We should leave for our training course soon, shouldn't we?
A. We still have a few minutes.
B. There's a map on the wall.
C. Two sessions per day.
Number 23.
Isn't there a limit on travel expenses?
A. To fix the vending machine.
B.
$100 per day.
C. Next to the travel agency.
Number 24.
When should I tell the director that I'm interested in the management position?
A. Yes, we're extending our business hours.
Didn't Andre direct the play?
C. I'm not on the hiring team.
Number 25.
The layout of the footwear department has changed.
A. There's a charging station in the cafe.
B. Yes, a three-bedroom apartment.
C. The store has a new manager.
Number 26.
Can you look at this month's revenue report?
A. The news program is informative.
B. I have some free time tomorrow afternoon.
C. He started that position in July.
Number 27.
Why haven't the windows been replaced yet?
A.
Not too much wind, no.
B. Look in the filing cabinet.
C. Did you see the cost estimate?
Number 28.
Isn't your suitcase going to be heavier than the permitted weight?
A. The building permit arrived today.
B. There are seats in the lobby.
C.
I'll have to pay a little bit extra.
Number 29.
Who manufactures the engines for our machines?
A. Koji is in charge of supplier contracts.
B. I'm sorry.
The storage room is full.
C. That's a cargo airplane.
Number 30.
Should we meet at the department store on 5th Street or the one on Grover Lane?
A. Let's ask Patricia first.
B. No, I don't mind.
C. How much does it cost?
Number 31.
Which band is playing at the club tonight?
A.
There's always a comedy show on Thursday nights.
B. Yes, I've played the piano for many years.
C. Their number one hit.
Part 3.
Directions.
You will hear some conversations between two or more people.
You will be asked to answer three questions about what the speakers say in each conversation.
Select the best response to each question and mark the letter A, B, C or D on your answer sheet.
The conversations will not be printed in your test book and will be spoken only one time.
Questions 32 through 34 refer to the following conversation.
Hi, Shenzhou.
I'm practicing my presentation in the conference room across the hall and the projector in there keeps shutting off.
I think it's overheating.
Has this happened to you?
Oh, that projector is old.
It really needs to be replaced.
If I were you, I'd just move to room 204 and practice there.
Also, that room has a window.
It's much nicer.
Okay, thanks.
By the way, you'll need a special cable to connect to the control panel in that room.
Here, you can use this one.
Just leave it plugged in when you're finished.
Number 32.
What problem does the woman describe?
Number 33.
What does the man suggest doing?
Number 34.
What does the man hand to the woman?
Questions 35 through 37 refer to the following conversation.
Hi, I'm Amanda Hoffman, and I'm on the panel of publishing experts.
I was told to check in here at the registration desk.
Yes, Ms.
Hoffman.
Welcome to the Portland Literary Conference.
Here's your registration packet, which includes a gift card to thank you for participating.
Oh, thank you.
Just to confirm, the panel discussion begins at 3 p.m., right?
Yes, but we do ask that all panel members arrive ten minutes beforehand.
I hope you enjoy the conference.
Number 35.
What industry does Amanda Hoffman work in?
Number 36.
According to the man, what is included in the registration packet?
Number 37.
What does the man tell the woman to do?
Questions 38 through 40 refer to the following conversation.
I'm looking for a gift for my brother's birthday party this weekend.
He loves teas and you have so many varieties.
Well, I could recommend a quality brand if you know what type he enjoys.
Oh, I'm not sure.
Hmm.
Maybe I should get him a gift card so he can choose his own.
That's a good idea.
I'll get one for $50.
Do your cards have an expiration date?
Yes, we ask that they be used within one year of purchase.
Number 38.
What event will the woman attend this weekend?
Number 39.
What does the man offer to do?
Number 40.
What does the woman ask about?
Questions 41 through 43 refer to the following conversation with three speakers.
Thanks for meeting with us, Ms.
Raj.
We're excited to learn about the product your company has developed for factories like ours.
I'm happy to tell you about it.
It's an application to monitor factory machines.
It identifies problems in operations and generates a report about the efficiency of each machine.
That sounds great.
We have about 100 machine operators here.
How much training would be involved?
About an hour's worth.
We provide a video with step-by-step instructions.
Excellent.
That's good to know.
Number 41.
Why is the woman visiting?
Number 42.
What did the woman's company design?
Number 43.
What does the woman say her company can provide?
Go on to the next page.
Questions 44 through 46 refer to the following conversation.
Hi, I'd like to go to the Baldwin Theater.
The address is 91 Circle Drive.
Sure, but did you know they're resurfacing Circle Drive?
I just dropped someone off in that area.
Oh, really?
I've got a ticket to a play, and the show starts at 7.30.
They don't let you in if you're late.
Well, let me see.
I can turn on to Felton Street.
and cut over to Lancaster Drive.
It's a little out of the way, but it'll get you close to the theater.
Number 44.
Who most likely is the man?
Number 45.
What is causing a problem?
Number 46.
What does the man say he will do?
Questions 47 through 49 refer to the following conversation.
Do you have a minute to discuss the budget for the upcoming Vancouver meeting?
I've looked over the travel request you submitted for your team.
Last year we sent only two representatives.
Ms.
Tamura has just given us approval to send three.
In fact, the clients are looking to expand their online service options, and the third representative we're bringing is particularly knowledgeable about that.
Okay, I guess we'll have to find savings somewhere else then.
I've already looked into some new meeting venues.
The Renova Hotel is offering discounted corporate rates this month.
Number 47.
Why does the woman say...
Last year we sent only two representatives.
Number 48.
According to the man, what do some clients want to do?
Number 49.
According to the man,
What is the Renova Hotel offering this month?
Questions 50 through 52 refer to the following conversation.
Good morning.
I wanted to meet today to discuss the recent decline in our museum's ticket sales.
You're the outreach coordinator.
So I'm hoping you might have some ideas on how we can attract more community involvement.
Well, I recently read an article about a museum in Chicago that has a room where visitors can paint on the walls.
It's become very popular.
We could try it here.
We have that huge room on the third floor that isn't being used.
That's a great idea.
Can you draft a list of the supplies we would need to make sure we have the budget for them?
Number 50.
What problem does the woman mention?
Number 51.
What does the man suggest doing?
Number 52.
What will the man most likely do next?
Questions 53 through 55 refer to the following conversation with three speakers.
Tilo, this is Ms.
Gow a new customer.
She's purchasing an upholstered sofa.
We just walked around our showroom, and she's decided on our Hudson model.
One of our best sellers.
It is really comfortable.
Can you assist her with the paperwork for our payment plan?
Sure.
Happy to help you, Ms.
Gow.
Are you getting the standard fabric?
No, I'd like to select a custom fabric.
Just so you know, the price will increase some with a custom order.
I think it's worth the extra cost.
It'll really brighten up my living room.
Wonderful.
Now, in order to set up a payment plan, I'll need to see some identification.
A driver's license will do.
Number 53.
Where most likely are the speakers?
Number 54.
According to the man, why will a product cost more?
Number 55.
What does the man request?
Questions 56 through 58 refer to the following conversation.
Good morning, Mr. Tong.
I'm here to check on my order.
How are the chairs coming along?
The machines have been assembling them.
They're almost ready.
Right over here.
Wow, they look so nice.
Look at the curved shape of the back.
The only way you can get that unique shape is by means of the specialized laser we use.
Amazing.
Can I also see the pull-out sofa?
Not right now, it's being treated with mineral oil.
But later today I should be able to take a photo and send it to you.
Number 56.
Where most likely are the speakers?
Number 57.
What feature does the man emphasize about some chairs?
Number 58.
What does the man say he will do later?
Questions 59 through 61 refer to the following conversation.
Hi, Sojin.
I just heard that Ms.
Yun is retiring next month.
I'll be sorry to see her go.
She was my mentor when I first joined the firm, and we've worked on dozens of projects together.
It's a bit hard to imagine our sales team without her.
Has anybody approached you about leading the team after she's gone?
Yes, and I've thought about it.
It's a big step up, even for someone like me who's worked in sales for eight years.
And Human Resources hasn't even posted the job description yet.
Well, we need someone with experience.
Number 59.
What will happen next month?
Number 60.
What department do the speakers work in?
Number 61.
What does the man imply when he says, we need someone with experience?
Question 62 through 64 refer to the following conversation and schedule.
Rajesh, it was nice to see you here in New York again this year.
Same here.
I look forward to attending the theater technology conference again next year.
I really enjoyed your talk, especially the information you provided on acoustics.
Is it published anywhere?
I'd like to have a closer look.
Actually, it is.
You can find the article in last November's issue of Theater Sound.
It's posted online.
Great.
I'll look it up.
Oh, my train leaves in 14 minutes.
I have to get going.
Safe travels, Camille.
Number 62.
Why are the speakers in New York?
Number 63.
What does the woman ask the man about?
Number 64.
Look at the graphic.
Where will the man travel to next?
Go on to the next page.
Question 65 through 67 refer to the following conversation and menu board.
Welcome to Orlando's Deli.
If you'd like to try one of our daily specials, they're on the board behind me.
Wow, that's a great menu.
The vegetable curry looks good.
Is it spicy?
No, it's very mild, but we just sold out, unfortunately.
In that case, I'll have the lasagna.
Great choice.
By the way, we just opened our new patio this week in case you'd like to sit outside.
Actually, it is a beautiful day, and your patio looks lovely.
Number 65.
What does the woman ask the man about?
Number 66.
Look at the graphic.
Which special does the woman order?
Number 67.
What will the woman most likely do next?
Question 68 through 70 refer to the following conversation and map.
I'm excited about our hike today here at Marina Park, and I'm so glad we got to the park early before it gets crowded.
Which trail should we hike?
Let's take a look at the map.
We're at the visitor center, and there's a shuttle that stops at different trailheads.
Right.
It looks like the Creek Trail and the Pond Trail are fairly short.
I'd like to do a more challenging hike.
Okay.
How about the waterfall trail?
That sounds good.
And look, there's a video about the park.
We can watch while we wait.
Number 68.
What is the woman happy about?
Number 69.
Look at the graphic.
How far will the speakers hike?
Number 70.
What can the speakers do while waiting for the shuttle?
Part 4.
Directions You will hear some talks given by a single speaker.
You will be asked to answer three questions about what the speaker says in each talk.
Select the best response to each question and mark the letter A, B, C, or D on your answer sheet.
The talks will not be printed in your test book and will be spoken only one time.
Question 71 through 73 refer to the following telephone message.
Hi, Ms.
Cho.
I'm calling from Springdale Light.
Yesterday, you ordered 24 of our purple solar lanterns for your upcoming event.
Unfortunately, our supplier won't be able to get us purple lanterns for another three weeks, so we only have yellow ones in stock.
We would like to offer you a 10% discount on them to apologize for this.
Please call us back to confirm whether you'd like the yellow solar lights, and we'll set them aside for you.
Number 71.
What did the listener do yesterday?
Number 72.
What problem does the speaker mention?
Number 73.
What does the speaker offer the listener?
Question 74 through 76 refer to the following talk.
Welcome to Ostawind Estate.
The former owner, Ms.
Youping Way, was a famous painter.
What's special about this estate is that Ms.
Wei designed it herself, including the landscaping.
We're asking volunteers to clear debris from the walkways around the gardens in preparation for the estate's first season as a public park.
You can pick up a bag and gloves from the patio area.
And remember, be sure to see me as you check out before you leave.
All volunteers are eligible for a complementary visitor pass that you can use to access the estate and attend any events held here all summer long.
Number 74.
According to the speaker, what is special about Osterwind Estate?
Number 75.
Why are the listeners at Osterwind Estate?
Number 76.
What will the listeners receive?
Question 77 through 79, refer to the following telephone message.
Good morning, Ms.
Espinoza.
This is Marcel Fournier.
It's Saturday morning, and I'm on my way to the airport.
This is a little out of the ordinary.
But I'm calling because, in my haste, I left a note with Mr. Hong's mobile phone number on my office desk.
He's picking me up from the airport, and I'll be stuck if I can't reach him.
I'll need you to go into the office and text me with the number.
I know this is inconvenient.
I'll check my messages once I land in San Diego.
Number 77.
Who most likely is the listener?
Number 78.
Why does the speaker say, I know this is inconvenient.
Number 79.
What will the speaker do when he arrives in San Diego?
Questions 80 through 82 refer to the following talk.
Hi, everyone.
Thanks for watching today.
If you're new to my channel, you should know that my videos focus on ways that we can repurpose common objects so that they don't end up in landfills.
In this video, you'll learn how to make candles from old and leftover crayons.
Your first step is to collect the items you'll need.
You may already have some old crayons around the house, or you can ask your friends and neighbors for theirs.
I'll be covering a lot of steps, but don't worry, a full written version of the instructions is available on my website.
I recommend downloading those later for future reference.
Number 80.
What does the speaker say her videos are usually about?
Number 81.
What first step does the speaker mention?
Number 82.
According to the speaker, what can the listeners do on a website?
Go on to the next page.
Questions 83 through 85 refer to the following speech.
Thank you all for coming to this press conference.
As you know, the Grand Falls Bridge Improvement work has been underway for almost a year.
We're nearing the final stage of sanding and painting the newly built portions.
I know the fishing community has expressed concern over the potential environmental impact of this project on our local marine life.
Well, all required studies were conducted a year ago.
I'll take some questions now.
After that, our special events coordinator will discuss the bridge opening ceremony that's being planned.
Number 83.
What is the speech mainly about?
Number 84.
Why does the speaker say?
All required studies were conducted a year ago.
Number 85.
What will the next speaker discuss?
Questions 86 through 88 refer to the following telephone message.
Hello, Mr. Smith.
I hope you're getting settled into your office space in our building.
I'm calling about some large packages that arrived for your company last week.
We're keeping them for you in the storage room downstairs.
The lease agreement says management will hold packages for five days.
It's been ten days.
Please give me a call and let me know when you can come down to claim them so I can be there to open the storage room door for you.
Number 86.
Who most likely is the speaker?
Number 87.
Why does the speaker say, it's been 10 days?
Number 88.
What does the speaker offer to do?
Questions 89 through 91 refer to the following broadcast.
Our next story concerns Ferndale Valley.
It's well known that the area is one of the windiest locations in the region, and one company would like to take advantage of that natural energy source.
Breeze Capture hopes to install dozens of wind turbines by the end of next year.
The company is looking for local farmers who are interested in leasing summer fair land for the project.
In addition to being paid for the land use,
Participants will also be compensated for the energy that is generated by the turbines.
For more information, email info at breezecapture.com.
Number 89.
What is mentioned about Furndale Valley?
Number 90.
Who will participate in a project?
Number 91.
What will the participants receive?
Questions 92 through 94 refer to the following telephone message.
Hello, Mr. Kimura.
I'm calling from Ferris portable storage.
You recently ordered a container to store and move your household belongings in.
I'm calling to confirm that your container will be delivered tomorrow morning at 9 o'clock.
The driver will place it in your driveway.
After the delivery, if you could, please complete the customer feedback survey that we'll email you.
It will help us to improve our service.
Thanks.
Number 92.
What kind of business does the speaker work for?
Number 93.
Why is the speaker calling?
Number 94.
What does the speaker ask the listener to do?
Questions 95 through 97 refer to the following talk and cleaning supplies.
This is the custodial staff's cabinet for cleaning supplies.
As part of your training, you'll be expected to learn which cleaning solutions are used for different surfaces in the hotel, such as carpet and tile flooring.
The spray bottle on the top shelf, Baxlan, is for glass surfaces.
The product directly under the spray bottle is brand new.
It was just released this month, and it's excellent for polishing furniture.
Oh, and every Tuesday at 1 o'clock, a delivery truck brings any supplies that we're low on.
Don't forget to check that.
Number 95.
What is the purpose of the talk?
Number 96.
Look at the graphic.
Which product does the speaker say is new?
Number 97.
What happens at 1 o'clock on Tuesdays?
Questions 98 through 100 refer to the following excerpt from a workshop and flow chart.
Welcome back to this professional development workshop.
We'll continue from where we left off in our discussion on advertising through social media using videos and will end today's meeting by performing a group task.
Last week, we discussed the planning phase for a video marketing campaign.
Today, we'll move on to the production phase.
During this phase...
you'll need to ensure that high-quality equipment is used for lighting and camera work and that you have the best video editors you can get for the job.
We're very lucky to have an expert here today to talk about her experience with the process.
Please give your attention to Usha Madan.
Number 98 What is the topic of the course?
Number 99.
Look at the graphic.
Which step will be discussed today?
Number 100.
What will the listeners do next?